<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Julia Caffrey</title>
  <link href="http://rsms.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rsms.me/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-20T16:25:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://juliacaffrey.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Julia Caffrey</name>
    <email>jscaffrey@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>ASIS&T Annual</title>
    <link href="http://rsms.me/2016/03/01/asiststlouis.html"/>
    <updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rsms.me/2016/03/01/asiststlouis</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/dist/img/stlouisarch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;St. Louis Arch and Old Courthouse&quot; class=&quot;image-right&quot;&gt;
I recently gave a short talk on my trip to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asist.org/events/annual-meeting/annual-meeting-2015/&quot;&gt;ASIS&amp;amp;T Annual Meeting 2015&lt;/a&gt; in St. Louis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My trip was sponsored by the amazing folks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://neasist.org/&quot;&gt;NE ASIS&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; as their Travel Award student winner for the year. This year&amp;rsquo;s conference theme was on impact in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google slides below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1inQhsnZflF7HdNx9fJLFbkL9iJYdP4E6z5nQHfjCHLE/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Slides in &lt;a href=&quot;/dist/pdf/NEASISTTravelAwardPresentation.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Caffrey</name>
      <uri>http://juliacaffrey.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Competitive Usability Testing</title>
    <link href="http://rsms.me/2016/01/21/competitiveusabilitytesting.html"/>
    <updated>2016-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rsms.me/2016/01/21/competitiveusabilitytesting</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently conducted formal usability testing in a team setting with classmates for Dr. Rong Tang&amp;rsquo;s class Usability and User Experience Research.  I highly recommend Dr. Tang&amp;rsquo;s class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The testing I did was supervised by the brilliant User Research department at EBSCO, including Deidre Costello and Miranda Hunt.  My teammates were Lucy Taylor and Molly Rogers.  We conducted formal usability testing, a content inventory, and heuristic evaluation based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/ten-usability-heuristics/&quot;&gt;Jakob Nielsen&amp;rsquo;s 10 Usability Heuristics for User Interface Design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience was invaluable.  From my desk in Library Technology at Simmons College Library, I am often frustrated by how far behind libraries are: our websites, our software (namely our ILS products), our open source solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Test Competitively?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Users bring expectations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t expect that users&#39; information needs and habits aren&amp;rsquo;t already shaped by their everyday experiences the moment they walk through our gates or access our sites.  Those &amp;ldquo;unsophisticated&amp;rdquo; search terms entered, their expectations for what information they expect to see and where &amp;ndash; these are all shaped by forces that we, as stewards of the resources we offer, can realistically lose sight of.  So why not test?  And while we&amp;rsquo;re at it, why not ask the tough questions about what users prefer and why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The benefit of environmental scanning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your library is not a bubble.  While your library might not compete with the library down the street for funding, but similar resources are available to our peers.  It&amp;rsquo;s in our best interest to not only compare our professional experiences with the tools we use on a day-to-day basis, but how our users experience them.  This not only gives us an understanding of how those tools are used, but gives us information to pass on to our vendors so that they can also remain competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Librarians already have a healthy culture of sharing resources through publications and conferences and other informal means of professional development.  Competitive usability testing through already strong networks would nudge library systems and tools toward sorely needed, &lt;em&gt;meaningful progress&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Caffrey</name>
      <uri>http://juliacaffrey.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>UX & You</title>
    <link href="http://rsms.me/2016/01/09/uxandyou.html"/>
    <updated>2016-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rsms.me/2016/01/09/uxandyou</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/dist/img/uxyou.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;With fellow case study presenters at UX &amp; You&quot; class=&quot;image-right&quot; style=&quot;width: 55%; margin-top: 0;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://neasist.asist.org/&quot;&gt;NE ASIS&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Annual Conference UX &amp;amp; You focused on user experience design and research.  The conference fell right at the end of a successful semester studying the topic with Professor Rong Tang at Simmons College.  For that reason, my classmates and I presented our projects conducted over the course of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend visiting NE ASIS&amp;amp;T&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://neasist.asist.org/2016/01/08/user-experience-design-research-conference-roundup/&quot;&gt;UX &amp;amp; You Conference Roundup&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about their projects and for slides from my presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Caffrey</name>
      <uri>http://juliacaffrey.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Reality at the Reference Desk</title>
    <link href="http://rsms.me/2013/11/01/realityatthereferencedesk.html"/>
    <updated>2013-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rsms.me/2013/11/01/realityatthereferencedesk</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Student Requests Are Time-Bound&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Reference Interview&amp;rdquo; theory in the classroom will prepare you very well for in depth and quality reference service. Real reference transactions are quick or depend on the imminent deadline, class, dinner, or what have you.  I try to feel this out in the first minute of the transaction and navigate from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;So, about the printer&amp;hellip;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get ready to get to know your library&amp;rsquo;s printing environment really quickly.  In my first Reference shift I learned that &amp;ldquo;reference&amp;rdquo; can be 40% helping patrons print or save properly and get on with their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which can be awesome, if you make it awesome by approaching the question with the same commitment to access to technology as you would to do to access to information.  I like to walk the patron to the machine, hear what they experienced and compare it to expected behavior, and walk them through the rest of the process.  Again, there is a certain amount of situation reading here.  What is their comfort level? Can you meet them there and gently nudge them further to learn something or feel more confident?  The same principles of reference service and information literacy applies here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Caffrey</name>
      <uri>http://juliacaffrey.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
</feed>